# losif V.

## Software Engineer

London, UK

in iosify iosify iosify

Hey there I'm losif, a senior Backend Engineer with experience in creating complete projects from start to finish in Node.js and PHP. I write code as clean as possible so that the next dev will be happy to maintain it and the junior will quickly grasp it. Curious by nature, I'm always willing to learn new things, so these days I spend my evenings working with Solidity and Hardhat on creating Blockchain smart contracts.

### SKILLS -

Languages			F	Frameworks				Admin		
Node.js	Typescript	PHP		Laravel	Express	Serverless		AWS	Terraform	CI / CD
Solidity	bash	bash		Hardhat				Docker	Shell Scripting	

### WORK EXPERIENCE (11) -

Aug 2022 - Current

### Software Engineer at Casa4

Contractor for various clients on different projects & extra work on personal projects

- Contractor for various clients on different projects, mainly focused on pure PHP, Laravel and Node.JS
  applications with different levels of involvement from developing in a team to the sole actor building the
  application and setting up the deployment processes.
- Notable Projects/Clients:
- ElectroRent: Complex tool-renting platform written in Laravel where I worked in a team of about 20 developers.
- Aliat Optic: Created a complete invoicing application from design to production. Using data from external FTP servers builds beautifully organised information easy to interact with. Built with AWS Lambda functions in Node.js using the Serverless Framework and DynamoDB.
- The Hurlingham Club: Was responsible with the migration of the system to their internally owned servers. This required the fixing of a lot of dev-ops related errors throughout the process.
- TicketTailor: Very complex PHP application, for which I contributed on improving the API with various bug-fixes and new features
- Technologies: Laravel, Node.js, AWS Lambda, MySQL, Terraform, AWS, VueJS, NuxtJS, CLI, Bash

Mar 2022 - Current

### Information Technology Advisor at Artetra

Startup that works towards bringing NFT's into online virtual galleries.

- I am contributing within business meetings on the IT side of the project.
- Most of the time is spent on translating the business requirements into actual features of the project by managing a small team of 3-4 developers.
- By having a general view of the project, I can help anyone who is stuck at any point.
- Technologies: Node.js, Hardhat, Solidity, AWS, Bash

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

### Software Engineer at True Compliance

Cloud Based Compliance Management System.

- Worked on building the main API of the system. Contributed to all the adjacent applications which constituted the entire ecosystem deployed as serverless functions on AWS with Laravel Vapor. Involved in designing some parts of the ecosystem's architecture.
- Some notable projects were a full reporting application which would create a report from any SQL provided. A system to serve real time data faster to the end client; by saving all the processed relational data into a no-sql database thus providing instant access to the transformed client-friendly set of the data.
- Technologies: PHP 7, PHP 8, Laravel 8, Laravel 9, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless
   Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2019 - Sep 2020

### Freelance Software Engineer at Casa4

Contractor for various clients on different projects & extra work on personal projects

- Created a complete invoicing application from design to production. This is reading data from XMLs deployed daily on external FTP servers, then joins and transforms them into beautifully organised information easy to interact with. Built with AWS Lambda functions in Node.js using the Serverless Framework and DynamoDB.
- Technologies: Serverless-Framework, Node.js, TypeScript, Laravel, VueJS, AWS, Lambda, EC2, S3, IAM, RDS, DynamoDB, API Gateway

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

### **Software Engineer** at Skin Analytics

Designing and developing our main Al Skin Analytics applications and keeping an eye on the AWS infrastructure.

- Biggest task was a migration from a no-sql database to a relational database which resulted in a 11x speed increase. All this was achieved with 100% transparency to the end user.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018

### Freelance PHP Application Developer at Casa4

Worked with various clients on Symfony or Laravel Projects.

- For each client I worked with, I was submitting pull requests in the first day.
- Biggest project was a complex tool-renting platform written in Laravel where I worked in a team of about
   20 developers
- Technologies: Laravel 5.6, Symfony, PHP 7.1, MySql, Git, PhpUnit

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

### PHP Application Developer / Dev-Ops at Woooba

Designing, developing & supporting client applications.

- Developed & maintained nationwide educational platforms. Designed and integrated various APIs.
- We built a complete financial management application.
- Managed all our DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup.
- Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, PHP 5.6, PHP 7.1, RESTful APIs, MySql, Git, CLI, VueJS, PhpUnit.

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

### PHP Application Developer at iQU Group

Marketing solutions for game developers.

- Created complete APIs from start to end as well as libraries which were used by my colleagues.
- Another smaller project was built with Java and PipelineDB.
- Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Symfony, API, MySQL, Git, Docker, CLI, PhpUnit, AngularJS, Java

Oct 2014 - Nov 2015

### PHP Application Developer at Project 89109

Online adult dating services.

Technologies: PHP, API, MySQL, CLI, Git, JS, jQuery.

Nov 2017 - Current

### Hardware Engineer / Dev-Ops at Hidden Hash (Personal Venture)

Family business dealing with mining crypto-currencies.

- Worked on Business model, Hardware setup, Software & security optimization/tweaks/updates,
   Performance fine tuning, Trading generated assets.
- Learned a lot about managing a larger than usual number of computers and hardware components.
- Built an open-source watchdog mechanism for certain types of graphic cards (https://github.com/iosifv/amd-vega-startup-scripts).

May 2005 - Dec 2014

**Photographer** at Saya Studio (Personal Venture)

Photography studio focusing mainly on weddings.

 Worked on Client handling, Marketing, Accounting, Management, Photographing, Retouching, Graphic design, Web-design.

### PROJECTS (3) -

#### **Terminal ToolBelt**

https://github.com/iosifv/terminal-toolbelt

- Open source collection of aliases and bash functions which I use.
- Organised in something which resembles a CLI Framework.

#### Silence

Open source tool for safely backing up ssh keys in a git repository

### iosifv.com

https://github.com/iosifv/iosifv-copy

- A copy of the repository of my website.
- Backend management system written in Laravel. Includes a photo gallery, quotes collection and a really cool json generated CV.

### **EDUCATION (2)** -

2010 - 2012

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

General management theories

2004 - 2009

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

C++ Java .NET SQL Lisp Prolog Xilinx Assembly x86 processor Electronics Physics

LANGUAGES

English Romanian Hungarian

Advanced Native speaker Beginner

INTERESTS

Hobbies

Chess HiFi Music

### REFERENCES

Photography

" https://www.linkedin.com/in/iosifv/ "

Publicly available on LinkedIn